《闪电侠》上季回顾
Last season, on "The Flash"...
爸爸妈妈
Hey, Mom and Dad.
如果你们在看这段画面
If you're watching this,
意味着出现了一些意外
it means that something went wrong.
妈妈  发生什么了
Mom, what's happening?
一个新的时间线开始了
A new timeline is setting in.
-谢谢你们为我做的一切  -我们爱你
- Thank you for everything. - We love you.
卡米拉  我不想再向你隐瞒了
Look, Kamilla, I don't want to keep this from you anymore.
如果作为震波是你想要的生活的一部分
If being Vibe is a part of the life you want,
我绝不会阻拦
I would never get in the way of that.
我要使用解药
I wanna take the cure.
我和冰霜杀手都会很想念震波的
Killer Frost and I are really gonna miss Vibe.
我也是
Me, too.
爸爸
Dad...
乔  我希望你来继任我的位子
I would like my replacement to be you, Joe.
-作为队长吗  -乔·韦斯特队长
- As captain? - Captain Joe West.
没有人可以阻挡既定的未来
None of you can stop what's been set into motion
因为无论你们做什么
because nothing you can do
闪电侠失踪  消失于危机之中
都会是徒劳
can alter what's about to happen.
2019年
这是整个系统范围的能量涌动
It's a system-wide power surge.
是从时间穹顶来的
It's coming from the time vault.
-我们遭到攻击了吗  -我不知道
- Are we under attack? - I don't know.
不管是什么  在我们离开那刻就开始了
Whatever's going on started the moment we left.
即便我并不完美
I wasn't perfect.
请一定要记住我爱你们
Please remember that I love you both...
直到永远
and I always will.
And I always will.
直到  直到  直到
And I always will. Always... Always...
巴里  诺拉的信息
Barry, Nora's message.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第一集
为什么每次我来找你
Why is it every time I come to visit
四个月之后
都会发生紧急情况
there's always a crisis?
超能力者的领域就是这样
Comes with the meta-territory.
时速750英里  他越来越快了
750 mph. He's getting faster.
这家伙到底是谁
Who is this guy, anyway?
我们的一个老朋友
An old family friend.
他叫做神速  来自未来
His name's Godspeed, and he's from the future.
他就像个冒牌的极速者
He's like a fake speedster.
那是什么
What's that?
真正的极速者
The real deal.
给他点颜色看看  巴里
Kick his butt, Barry!
看我好好收拾他
Done and doner.
你是谁  你来中城做什么
Who are you and what are you doing in Central City?
他和其他人一样  没有语言能力只有噪音
He's just like the others: no language skills, just noise.
-"棒"极了  -怎么回事
- Lovely. - What was that?
这是今夏我们抓到的第四个神速
The fourth Godspeed we've caught this summer
可仍然没有奥古斯特·哈特先生的踪迹
and still no sign of Mr. August Hart.
只不过是另外一个哑巴
Just another dummy
除了发出拨号噪音  无法做任何交流
who can't communicate anything beyond modem speak.
好了  我收工了
All right, I'm clocking out.
巴里  你把第四号神速送去铁山监狱吧
Why don't you drop off G4 at Iron Heights, Barry?
我想我们今天无法解开这个谜题了
I don't think we're figuring out this mystery today.
爸爸  这样真不错
This is nice, Dad.
我们应该多搞这样的活动
We should do this way more often.
同意
Agreed.
对了  差点忘了
Hey, before I forget,
恭喜你的《公民报》
congratulations on "The Citizen."
中城有几百万人口
Yeah, well, you know, there's millions of people in Central City
而我的报纸只有几十万订阅者
and I've only got a couple hundred thousand subscribers.
远不如《中城时报》受欢迎
You know, I'm no CCPN.
暂时还没有  但是十年之后
Well, not yet, but in about ten years
会获得很多普利策奖
it'll be a Pulitzer Prize-winning empire.
一步一步来  爸爸
Baby steps, Dad.
天哪  太好喝了
Mm, damn, this is good.
你知道你不能喝醉的
You know you can't get drunk.
这酒好喝到我根本不在乎
I don't even care, that's how good this is.
别害怕  派对开始了
Never fear, the party's here!
我们带了我拿手的安布罗西亚水果沙拉
We brought my famous ambrosia salad
还给拉尔夫带了素香肠
and veggie dogs for Ralph.
大伙  拉尔夫还在秘鲁
Guys, Ralph's still in Peru.
要么就是摩纳哥  还是得克萨斯
Or Monaco...or Texas?
还在查那个失踪人口的案子吗
All that for a missing person's case?
真是尽责尽心
That's dedication.
各位  我们在干什么呢
Guys, guys, what are we doing?
詹娜宝宝熟睡如小天使
Baby Jenna is napping like a little angel
而我这有奶油玉米  烤红薯
and I have creamed corn, I have candied yams,
还有羽衣甘蓝菜
I have collard greens.
-宝贝  我们开动吧  -好吃
- Baby, let's eat. - Yum!
-增强室怎么样了  -还有芝士通心粉吗
- How's the MAC coming? - There's mac and cheese too?
不  是精神增强室
No, the Mental Augmentation Chamber.
简单来说  就是它能让我们利用神速力
Basically, it allows us to tap into the Speed Force
来提高巴里的认知能力
to boost Barry's cognitive abilities.
能让他同时看到每一个场景里
It would allow him to see every possible outcome to a scenario
每一个潜在结果
at the same time.
就是极速思考
So speed-thinking.
就是说我们就能更快地抓到所有的坏人
Which means we'll be able to catch all the bad guys faster.
你这个夏天抓了那么多坏人
With all the ones that you brought in this summer,
巴里  地监官办公室都快跟不上你的速度了
Barry, the DA's office can barely keep up with you.
既然精神增强室已经弄好了
Hey, since the MAC's done,
我们应该去测试一下
we should take it for a test run.
当然不行
Absolutely not.
你知道我们还在做诊断
You know we're still working out diagnostics.
今晚我们可以花几个小时的时间
We could put in a few hours tonight,
先小试一下身手
get a head start.
巴里
Barry...
自从放下震波的身份起
If there's anything I've learned
要说我学会了什么
since leaving Vibe behind,
那就是我们都要维护工作和生活间的平衡
it's that we all have a work-life balance to protect,
而现在  我更倾向于多喝点啤酒
and right now, mine is tipping towards more beer.
而且  我还得调整主机
Besides, I still gotta tweak the mainframe
而且我不能没有我的...
and I can't do that without...
每一次都这样
Every time.
-平板电脑  -好吧
- My tablet. - Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要去拿啤酒喝
I'm gonna go get that beer.
上次和你们聊的时候
Hey, so the last time I talked to you guys,
你们好像还挺好的
you seemed good.
你们还好吗
You guys good?
一开始我们非常难过
we were devastated at first,
但诺拉只是暂时走了
but Nora's only gone for right now.
我们会有孩子
We're gonna have kids someday
然后再有第二个诺拉
and then we'll have another Nora.
知道我们还有第二次机会
Yeah, I think knowing that we have a second chance
让事情变得不一样了
makes all the difference.
我要走了  东区工业有人非法闯入
I gotta go, a break-in at Eastside Industrial.
老爸  我一直想问你
Dad, um, I meant to ask you,
后院那些纸盒
what did you do with those boxes
你弄到哪去了
that were in the back of the garage?
他终于扔掉了
Oh, he finally threw them away.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我要去打个电话
Okay, I gotta make a call.
抱歉各位  我其实也得走了
Guys, I'm sorry, I actually have to sneak out too.
我医学院的朋友需要我的支持
A friend of mine from med school needs my support.
谢谢你们请我来吃饭  非常美味
Thanks for having me, it was delicious.
拜  凯特琳
Bye, Caitlin.
你注意到没人留下帮忙收拾吗
You notice ain't nobody help clean up?
我叫拉姆齐·罗素
My name is Ramsey Rosso,
我母亲瑞秋·罗素医生
and my mother, Dr. Rachel Rosso,
是我的全部
was everything to me.
七岁的时候
When I was seven,
我骑自行车摔得很严重  那是我生日时
I skidded out pretty badly on a bike she bought me
她送我的
for my birthday.
想像一下  小孩子吓坏了  不仅膝盖擦伤
Imagine a scared kid with two scraped knees
鼻子还流血
and a bloody nose.
我妈找到我的时候  她把我扶起来
When Mum found me, she picked me right up,
拍拍我身上的灰
she brushed me off,
叫我回到车上继续骑
and told me to get back on my bike and ride.
我试了  但是不行
I tried, but I couldn't.
我就好像是瘫痪了
It was almost like I was paralyzed,
伤口很痛
it hurt so bad.
那时她和我说  伤口会愈合的
That's when she told me that I would heal.
我绝不能让一点点痛苦阻止我
That I must never let a little pain stop me
去到我人生中本该去的地方
from getting to where I needed to go in life,
她说得对
and she was right.
我愈合了
I did heal.
足以长大成人
Enough to grow up
并追随她的脚步
and follow in her footsteps.
虽然一个美丽的生命被夺走
And even though a beautiful life was cut short
但在她与自我治愈的战斗上失败时
when she lost her battle to heal herself...
她依然帮助我到达了我今天所在的位置
She is still helping me to get to where I need to go today.
因此  我永远感激
And for that, I will always be grateful.
谢谢你  乔纳森
Thank you, Jonathan.
拉姆齐  你好
Ramsey, hi.
我为你的失去感到遗憾
I'm so sorry for your loss.
你母亲是个无与伦比的女人
Your mother was an incredible woman.
我会想念她的
I'm gonna miss her.
你能来对她意义重大
It means so much that you came.
妈妈其实在你身上看到了一些她自己
Mum actually saw something of herself in you.
估计是因为你们都成就非凡
Probably because you're both overachievers.
你的手真凉
Your hands are so cold.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
对不起  我没事
Yeah, sorry, I'm fine.
应该只是着凉了
Um, probably just coming down with something.
我希望不是
Well, I hope not.
医生一般都不是好病人
Doctors make rubbish patients.
能见到你真好
It was nice to see you.
凯瑟琳
Eh, Caitlin?
最近事情有些  疯狂
Things have been a bit, um, crazy.
你想没事来喝杯茶吗
Do you fancy coming around for a cuppa sometime?
你知道的  正式地叙叙旧
You know, for a proper catch-up.
我现在真的需要有个人可以聊天
I could really use someone to talk to right now.
当然  什么时候都可以
Of course, any time.
给我打个电话就好
Just give me a call.
我的记录上显示你父亲的东西
Well, my log says that your father's stuff
大概就在这附近
should have ended up somewhere around here.
在这里
There it is.
一定很重要吧
Must be pretty important.
是的
Yeah, it is.
谢谢你
Thanks.
抓住
H-hang on!
我抓住你了
I've got you!
抓住
Hang on!
你没事吧
You okay?
什么东西
What the hell?
我昨晚好想你  你还好吗
I missed you last night. Are you sure you're okay?
还好
Yeah.
你来这里是要做什么
What were you doing out here anyway?
我在追踪一个线索
I was following up on a lead.
《公民报》收到一个线报
"The Citizen" Got a tip
说发生了一系列垃圾场盗窃案
that there were a series of junkyard robberies.
居然有人会因为垃圾被偷报警
People file police reports for stolen trash?
是啊  你知道的
Yeah, well, you know,
这里不全是垃圾
not everything that's here is garbage.
这里全是垃圾
Everything here is garbage!
我讨厌垃圾
I hate garbage.
好吧  和捉鬼敢死队玩吧
Okay, have fun with Ghostbusters.
我们回家见
I'll see you at home.
你找到什么了吗
What do you got?
这地方堆满了  不是双关
This site is littered-no pun intended--
伽马射线和磁星域
with gamma rays and magnetar fields.
你什么意思  袭击爱瑞丝的是...
What are you saying? Iris was attacked by a--
对  一个黑洞
Yeah, a frakkin' black hole.
这信息量太大不好消化啊
That is a whole lot of information to disseminate.
以前从没有人从黑洞
No one's ever extrapolated this much data
解析出过这么多数据
from a black hole before.
我们可能成为第一个
We can be the first.
别这样  我们可是闪电侠小队
Come on, we're Team Flash!
你在他咖啡里放了什么
What did you put in his coffee?
好吧  一个黑洞突然出现
Okay, a black hole just showed up
差点吞掉爱瑞丝
and nearly swallowed Iris.
那咱们就开始计算  找出它去哪了
So let's crunch the numbers, find out where it went.
抱歉  我们在看同一个屏幕吗
I'm sorry, are we looking at the same screen?
为这些数据创造一个算法就像是
Creating a search algorithm for this is gonna be like
破解一个用密码所组成的谜语
deciphering a mystery wrapped up in an enigma.
好消息是
Then it's a good thing
"谜"是我的中间名
that "Mystery" Is my middle name.
我叫德比
The name's Dibny...
拉尔夫·德比
Ralph Dibny.
欢迎回来  拉尔夫
Welcome back, Ralph.
-见到你真好  -西服不错啊
- It's good to see you, man. - Nice threads.
-你哪里弄的  -在欧泊市买的
- Where'd you get them? - Picked this up in the Opal.
一个失踪人口案
A missing person's case
让你跑到欧泊市去了
sent you all the way to Opal City?
更远  我的朋友
And beyond, my friend.
整个夏天当着卧底和有钱的精英们
A summer spent undercover rubbing Rolexes
一起盘劳力士度过的
with the wealthy elite.
你们知道"游艇"的发音
Did you guys know it's pronounced "Yacht"
不是"浮艇"吗
and not "Yah-kt"?
-知道  -天哪  我想你了
- Yep. - God, I missed you.
无论如何  跟踪任何能帮助我解释
Anyway, just following any leads that might help
苏·迪尔邦失踪的线索
explain the disappearance of Sue Dearbon.
我觉得我从没见过你对一个案子这么投入
I don't think I've ever seen you this devoted to a case.
我也没有  但这个真是一个悲剧
Me neither, but this one is a real tragedy.
或许是他父母
Maybe it was the look of desperation
求我去寻找他们的女儿时
in her parents' eyes when they begged me
那绝望的眼神驱使着我
to find their daughter.
话说回来  中城有什么新鲜事吗
So, uh, what's new in Central City?
我们试图追踪一个黑洞
We are trying to track a black hole.
当然了
Of course you are.
我们正要开始给这些数据解码
We were just about to start decoding this data stream.
抱歉  对不起
Ugh, I'm sorry, sorry.
我最近总是出现这些随机的霜爆
Been having these random frost-outs lately.
-持续多久了  -整个夏天
- For how long? - All summer.
最近这两天已经发生两次了
It's happened twice in the last couple of days.
凯特  你多半是劳累过度了
Cait, you're probably overworked.
或许休息一下吧
Maybe take a time out?
我的一个朋友正好想请我去喝杯咖啡
- A friend of mine did want to meet for coffee.
-拉姆齐吗  -是的
- Ramsey? - Yeah.
父母去世从来都不轻松
It's never easy losing a parent.
或许你可以帮帮他
Maybe you should take him up on it.
我给他打个电话
I'll give him a call.
找到了
Ah, found it.
里伍德和新布莱顿垃圾场的盗窃报告
Theft report for Leawood and New Brighton junkyard.
你看  我有系统
See, I have a system.
你是个囤积狂  但是我爱你
You're a hoarder, but I love you.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
闪电侠和XS携手击败蝉
看起来这些
Huh, these don't seem
跟黑洞都没什么联系
to have anything to do with the black hole.
就是一些普通的人类盗窃
They're just run-of-the-mill human thefts.
你现在有了嫌疑人的名单了
Well, you have a list of persons of interest,
总之
in any case.
是啊  谢谢你
Yeah, thank you.
我这就去调查
Um, I'll get right on this.
爱瑞丝
Iris?
-怎么了  -没什么
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
我也不太清楚  可能那个黑洞让我
I--I don't know, maybe I'm still a little shaken up
还是有些惊恐
from the black hole.
我会好起来的  多谢
I'll be fine, thank you.
你还记得我拿铁里都放什么
You remembered how I like my lattes.
加一点肉桂  就像我妈妈一样
With a bit of cinnamon, just like Mum.
你知道吗  在她所有中城医院的实习医生里
You know, of all her CC Hospital residents,
她真的特别喜欢你
she really took a special liking to you.
她是第一个
She was the first person
看出来我喜欢尖端科技的人
to realize that I was into cutting-edge tech.
是她的推荐信让我
It was her letter of recommendation
开始了在尖端科研实验室的生涯
that started my career at S.T.A.R. Labs.
我没能救她  凯特
I couldn't save her, Cait.
被迫看着她的身体渐渐背叛她
Had to watch as her body betrayed her.
你知道噬血细胞综合征的原理吗
Do you know how HLH works?
那你就知道癌症真的会
Then you know the cancer literally boils you
从内而外的把你毁掉
from the inside out.
你能想象到那会是什么感觉吗
Can you imagine what that must have felt like?
看着她遭受折磨
Watching her suffer...
这是我对她最后的印象
That's my last memory of her.
不要让这成为你最后的印象
Don't let it be.
你在葬礼上说的她是多么勇敢
What you said at the funeral about how brave she was?
记住那些
Remember that.
我说谎了
I lied.
事实上  她是个懦夫
Truth is, she was a coward.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
作为一名医生  她知道存活几率渺茫
As a doctor, she knew her chances of surviving were slim,
所以她开始完成愿望清单上的事情
so she just started ticking things off her bucket list.
这难道不是一件好事吗
Isn't that a good thing?
她本应该战斗到最后
She should have gone down fighting.
相反  她选择了逃避
Instead, she ran away.
我没有
I didn't.
在噬血细胞综合征中  白血球
In HLH, white blood cells attack
攻击身体的免疫系统
the body's immune system.
确诊后的平均生存率
A median survival rate after diagnosis
是二到六个月
was two to six months.
不再如此了
Not anymore.
天哪  这是潜在的治疗方法
Oh, my God, this is a potential cure.
但加强身体防御能力
But what's the bonding agent
的粘合剂是什么
strengthening the body's defenses?
暗物质
Dark matter.
我知道你在想什么  凯特
I know what you're thinking, Cait.
我一开始也这么想
I thought the same thing, too-- at first.
但我做了几个月的模拟
But I have been running simulations for months,
结果都是一样的
and they all show the same results.
我的药物有用
My cure will work.
或违背他们的意愿把他们变成了超能力者
Or turn them into meta-humans against their will.
但我能拯救生命
But I can save lives.
我只需要暗物质来开始人体实验
I just need the dark matter to start human trials.
这才是你想和我喝咖啡的原因
And that's why you wanted to get coffee with me.
尖端科研实验室有我进行下一步
S.T.A.R. Labs has the dark matter I need
需要的暗物质  你们能拿到
to take the next step; you have access to it.
拉姆齐  你的研究具有开创性
Ramsey, your research, it's groundbreaking,
但使用暗物质
but using dark matter?
那就免谈了
That's a deal-breaker.
但你能用它做超能力者解药
It wasn't when you made the meta-human cure.
那是不同的  我们是在保护他们
That was different. We were trying to protect them.
那我们其他人呢
Well, what about the rest of us?
对不起  真的对不起
I'm sorry. I really am.
但我的答案还是不行
But my answer is still no.
她不必死的  凯特
She didn't have to die, Cait.
任何得了噬血细胞综合征的人都不必
No one with HLH does,
因为你可以帮我制止它
because you could help me stop it.
冰霜  你在哪
Frost, where are you?
-你感觉如何  -像已经死了一样
- How you feeling? - Like I should be dead.
不会的  我们是闪电侠小队
That's not gonna happen. We're Team Flash.
我们总是互相照顾
We always watch each other's backs.
我们会确保彼此的安全
We always keep each other safe.
同时  在这里的真实世界
Meanwhile, over here in the real world,
黑洞一直在变大
our black hole keeps growing up.
它下次出现  就不只是吉特咖啡店了
Only next time it pops up, it won't just be Jitters.
整座城市都会有危险
The whole city could be in danger.
为什么会在吉特咖啡店外出现呢
Why did this thing show up outside Jitters, anyway?
咖啡店和废品场有什么共同点
What does a coffee shop have in common with a junkyard?
我知道谁可以告诉我们答案
I think I know who can tell us.
我追踪了中城警局的
Okay, so I followed up with CCPD's list
废品场抢劫名单
of junkyard robberies.
其中十个是嫌犯
Ten of them were persons of interest,
九个是职业罪犯  但这个家伙
nine were career criminals, but this one guy,
是科学家  因偷旧实验器材被逮捕后
a scientist, was let go with a warning
给了一个警告就被放走了
after being caught stealing old lab equipment.
闪电侠小队  来见见切斯特·P·朗克
Team Flash, meet Chester P. Runk.
尖端科研实验室
大家闹起来
Hey, what up, party people?
欢迎来到一切皆受欢迎的世界
Welcome to a world where all are welcome
任何事  包括科学上不可能的
and anything, including the scientifically impossible,
也可能发生
can and probably will happen.
我是你们的伙伴
I'm your boy
切克  切克  切克  切斯特
Chugga-Chugga-Chugga-Chugga Chester...
Healthyskeptic45:这家伙绝对是个#疯子科学家#
我好喜欢他
I really like him.
拥有尖端的物理知识
With knowledge from the bleeding edge of physics
超  超  超尖端
and beyond-beyond-beyond.
我还在练习那个回声
I've been working on that echo.
和往常一样  我能量满满是因为
And--and yes, as usual, I am fueled by some...
DerekIsAWESOME6776:超赞的回声
喝了那家
mm, damn fine coffee
大家都喜欢的咖啡
from everyone's favorite beanery.
J-MONEY:打赌这是他今天喝的第六杯
由一个特殊的人
Poured, of course, to, uh, perfection
完美地倒给我
by a certain special someone.
WookieLover77:你约娜塔莉出去了吗
没有  WookieLover77  我
Uh, no, WookieLover77, I...
我还没约她
I have not asked her out yet,
但我有集点卡
but I got my punch card, okay?
再来三杯震波卡布奇诺  我就展开行动
Three more Vibe-achinos and I'm making my move, baby.
我要下手了  宝贝
I'm making my move, baby.
WookieLover77:你最好快点开始行动
我要下手了  宝贝
I'm making my move, baby!
他谈了好久娜塔莉
Okay, he talks about Natalie for a while, so...
看这个
There we go.
他是在制造我想的那个东西吗
Is he building what I think he's building?
快看  信徒们
Behold, believers:
一台由调制中微子充电器供能的重力波发射器
a gravitational wave emitter powered by a modulated neutrino charger.
也就是说
In other words,
"是时候呼叫外星人了"
"Time to call some aliens."
-这是他在车库里造出的  -材料只有垃圾
- He built this in his garage? - Using nothing but trash.
简直是个传奇  他要启动它了
What a legend. Oh, he's turning it on.
不好
Uh--uh, no.
不  不应该是这样
No, no, no, that's not supposed to do that.
糟了  等一下
Oh, crap. Uh, hold on.
好吧  从我们这位切斯特身上
Okay, not exactly getting the supervillain vibe
并没有感受到超级反派的气息
from our boy Chester here.
他不小心打开了一个黑洞
He opened a black hole by accident.
切斯特怎么样了  他还好吗
And what about Chester? Is he okay?
警方报告显示他被急救人员送到了急诊室
Well, police reports show that EMTs took him to the ER,
之后就没有消息了
but then after that the trail goes cold.
有一个小问题
Just a tiny question here:
我们要怎样摧毁一个黑洞
how do we destroy a black hole?
扫描完成
结果  负值
我不是医生
Well, I am not a doctor,
但是我猜在这种情况下
but I'm gonna assume in this case
"负值"意味着好消息
that "Negative" means a positive.
可我还搞不清为什么我能力不起作用
Not if it means being clueless about why my powers won't work.
最近发生了什么不正常的事情吗
Did anything out of the ordinary happen recently?
我昨天参加了我朋友拉姆齐妈妈的葬礼
I went to my friend Ramsey's mom's funeral yesterday.
葬礼上有什么不寻常的事吗
Anything unusual about the service?
没有  是一位值得尊重的女士的葬礼
No, it was a lovely service for an inspiring woman.
然后今天  我差点被吸入黑洞
Then, today, I nearly got sucked into oblivion.
冰霜美人曾经像这样拒绝出现过吗
Has our frosty femme fatale ever refused to come out like this before?
我记得上一次是我父亲刚刚去世之后
The last time I can think of is right after my dad died.
就是这样
Right.
所以你认为葬礼加上差点被吸入黑洞
So you think funeral plus nearly getting sucked into a black hole
表明冰霜杀手害怕死亡
equals Killer Frost is afraid of dying?
有可能
Maybe...
但是我知道我们会想出解决办法的
but I know we're gonna figure this out.
这地方太恐怖了
This place creeps me out.
这个能帮你克服恐惧吗
Will this sort you out?
和你做生意很愉快
Nice doing business with you.
瑞秋·罗素
挚爱的母亲
不管是谁惹了你
Whoever pissed you off
都不再会是问题了
won't be a problem anymore.
切斯特·P·朗克住在这里吗
Chester P. Runk is here?
病房护士说他来这里时就犯着紧张症
Ward nurses say he's been catatonic since he arrived.
只有无意识的肌肉痉挛
Just involuntary muscle spasms.
切斯特
Chester?
我叫爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦  是一名记者
My name is Iris West-Allen, I'm a reporter.
切斯特  你能听到我说话吗
Chester, can you hear me?
他是我们唯一的线索
He was our only lead.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
你昨晚失去了诺拉的某个东西  对吗
You lost something of Nora's last night, didn't you?
某个乔不小心扔掉的东西
Something that Joe accidentally threw away,
最后进了那片垃圾场里
it ended up at that junkyard.
我只是太想她了
I just miss her so much.
每一天  每一分钟
Every day, every minute.
我知道这很自私
And I know that is selfish because...
因为总有一天我会再次见到诺拉
one day I may get to see Nora again.
但那不是我们的诺拉  你知道吗
But it won't be our Nora, you know?
不是那个我们认识的  我们了解的
The one that we knew, the one that we have pictures of,
我们爱着的诺拉
the one that we grew to love, you know...
那个诺拉永远地消失了
That Nora is gone forever.
我想就是因为这样  我就...
And I guess because of that you know, I just...
不知道自己应该有什么感受
I don't know how I'm supposed to feel.
爱瑞丝  你不能因为总有一天会再见到诺拉
Iris, you do not get to cheat the grieving process
就拒绝接受悲伤的过程
just because you know you're gonna see Nora again someday.
你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
我只是不知道怎样用语言表达自己的感受
I guess I just haven't been able to put into words how I've been feeling.
爱瑞丝
Iris?
怎么了
What is it?
吉特咖啡馆外
出现神秘黑洞
是切斯特
It's Chester.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你看到的是世界上第一台
You're looking at the world's first
反质量角动量干扰器
inverse mass angular momentum disruptor,
我们也可以就叫它星状手榴弹
but we can just call it a stellar grenade.
酷
Cool.
所以这个能摧毁黑洞吗
So this will destroy the black hole?
只要黑洞不再变大
As long as it doesn't get much bigger,
它会逆转黑洞的巨大吸力
this will reverse the hole's mass-collecting properties,
让它内爆
causing it to... Implode.
只要把它扔进黑洞的视界范围内
Just toss it in the event horizon;
但要小心别弄到身上
hasta lasagna, don't get any on you.
我们不能这么做
We can't.
如果我们摧毁黑洞  也会杀死切斯特
If we destroy it, we're gonna kill Chester too.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
确定  电晕光圈的闪烁跟
Yeah, the corona's flair matched
切斯特手指的节奏完全吻合
the exact cadence of Chester's fingers.
所以黑洞跟切斯特有关联
So the black hole and Chester are connected?
实际上  我觉得切斯特就是黑洞
Actually, I think Chester is the black hole.
看看这个
Watch this:
通常  刺激通过感觉区进入大脑
so normally, stimuli enters the brain through the sensory area,
往上进入颞叶  然后再绕回来
goes up to the temporal lobe, and then back around,
看看切斯特的大脑发生了什么
but watch what happens in Chester's brain.
刺激首先出现在右边区域
It starts in the right area,
但是只转了一半  就消失了
but halfway through its rotation, it disappears.
我想我知道它去哪了
I think I know where it's going.
你们看到的是负离子能量
You're looking at a map of the negative ionic energy
在黑洞内的分布图
inside the black hole.
看看能量脉冲沿着它的卷须运动时会发生什么
Watch what happens when an energy pulse travels along its tendrils.
看到它是如何半路中断的了吗
See how it stops halfway?
负离子能量
黑洞是切斯特的另一半大脑
The black hole is the other half of Chester's mind.
是他的意识
It's his consciousness.
也许它会在他寄托了
Maybe it's been showing up in places
特殊情感的地方出现
that hold an emotional attachment for him,
比如他去偷项目材料的垃圾场
like the junkyard where he stole stuff for his projects.
他喜欢吉特咖啡馆的一个女孩
He's got a crush on a girl at Jitters.
好  所以我们要做的就是
Okay, so all we have to do is
把切斯特的大脑弄出黑洞
get Chester's mind out of the black hole,
让它跟他的身体重新结合
reunite it with his body,
只要他的情况稳定了
and once his condition stabilizes,
黑洞应该就会坍塌
the black hole should just collapse.
没错  但医学院没教过这些
Right, but they don't exactly teach that in med school.
是  但我们不能看着切斯特死
Okay, but we can't just let Chester die.
我们总得做些什么
We have to do something.
听着  我不想提这个
Look, I don't like saying it,
但我觉得我们必须考虑一下
but I think we need to consider it.
西斯科  我知道你在想什么
Cisco, I know where you're going.
你也知道我们已经有了在黑洞变大之前
And you know we already have a way of beating this
消灭它的方法
before it gets any bigger.
这没的讨论
We're not discussing this.
你觉得我想说这些吗
You think I like saying this?
我不想  但如果我们不能马上找到解决办法
I don't, but if we don't find a solution for this and find one now,
我们就只能二选一了
we're gonna have to make a choice down the line,
是选择切斯特
and it's either gonna be Chester
还是中城的所有市民
or it's gonna be everyone in Central City.
我不会再抛弃任何人了
I'm not losing anyone else!
我们再想想别的法办法
I'm--let's find another way.
拉尔夫
紧急  核聚变熔化了
需要冰霜杀手尽快赶到
哪里溶化了
Where's the meltdown?
我们得谈谈
We gotta talk.
你有什么问题
What is your problem?
我的问题是  我们需要你的时候
My problem is, we needed you,
你蜷缩在你那孤独的雪松树里
and you were holed up in your Snow-tress of Solitude.
在吉特那时你都拒绝出来
I mean, you even refused to come out at Jitters.
当时有闪电侠在  走廊谈心就免了吧
Flash was there, so spare me the little hallway chat--
而且我不怕死
and I'm not afraid of dying.
我知道  但你害怕活着
I know that, but you are afraid of living.
托马斯的死  葬礼  吉特发生的事
Thomas' death, the funeral, what happened at Jitters:
凯特琳身上发生的一切
all those things happened to Caitlin.
她也曾带领着她的高中辩论队
She also led her high school debate team
接二连三地夺冠
to back-to-back championships.
她上医学院  嫁给罗尼
She went to med school. She married Ronnie.
这都是她的记忆
Those are her memories.
是的  我知道  我也在场
Yes, I know. I was there.
你想说什么
What's your point?
拥有凯特林的记忆跟你自己拥有不一样
Having Caitlin's memories isn't the same as having your own.
就像你能感同身受一样
Like you'd know anything about that.
我知道当思考者挟持了我的身体后
I know it sucked sitting courtside for the Thinker show
只能袖手旁观很不好受
when he hijacked my body,
我认为自从托马斯死后
and I think that you've been going through something similar
你经历着相同的感受
since Thomas died.
在参加那场葬礼以后
And after being at that funeral,
看着那个女人在她生命的最后几天如此充实
seeing that woman live the last days of her life to the fullest,
我认为那让你
I think that made you
想要从现在开始你最好的人生
want to start living your best life right now.
那不是我该做的  好吗
That's not my gig, okay?
我与坏人战斗  保护小凯的安全
I fight the bad guys, keep Caitie safe,
然后回到我的笼子里
and then go back in my cage.
我只能默然接受
I just have to deal with it.
你想过去问问凯特琳她的感受吗
Have you thought to ask Caitlin how she feels?
她能说什么
What's she gonna say?
"来吧  冰霜  你来掌舵"
"Go ahead, Frost, take the wheel."
只有一种方法能找到答案
There's only one way to find out.
巴里  我认为我们是时候面对真相了
You know, Barry, I think it's time we faced the truth.
我不能放弃切斯特
I can't give up on Chester.
不  我是指
No, I meant...
诺拉的事
About Nora.
我知道我们一直在说我们没事
Look, I know we keep saying that we're fine,
但我还是想念从前的诺拉  巴里
but I still miss the Nora that was, Barry,
不是将来的诺拉  我认为你也是
not the Nora that will be, and I think that you do too.
我认为这是你整个夏天都努力工作的原因
I think that's why you've been working so hard all summer.
我想着如果我能通过保护人们
I thought if I could keep people safe,
来弥补我对她的思念
that it would make up for how much I miss her.
想想这个夏天所有的工作和加班加时
Think all the work this summer and the long hours,
逼着自己  逼着整个团队
pushing myself, pushing the team...
如此我才能避开我最害怕的
It's so I could avoid what scares me the most...
我永远也想不开的
that I'll never get over this.
没有针对我们这种经历的互助小组
There is no support group for what we're experiencing.
你知道我为什么在那个垃圾场吗
You know why I was at that junkyard?
我把我的紫色夹克弄丢了
I lost my purple jacket.
我很想
And I was obsessed
找回它  因为
with getting it back because...
我想着
You know, in my mind...
诺拉需要它
Nora needs it.
她需要它来成为XS
You know, she needs it to become XS.
当那东西吞掉它  就...
And when that thing swallowed it, just--
有那么一秒钟
just for, like, a tiny second,
我想让它也吞了我
I wanted it to swallow me too.
我们能挺过去的唯一方法
You know, the only way we're gonna get through this
就是一起背负这个包袱
is if we carry this burden together.
巴里  这是唯一的方法
It's the only way, Barry.
我们没时间了
We just ran out of time.
所以我们怎样从黑洞中取出切斯特的意识
Okay, so how do we get Chester's consciousness out of the black hole?
构成切斯特思想的电脉冲
Well, the electrical impulses that make up Chester's mind
刚刚越过黑洞的门槛
are just past the black hole's threshold,
但是由于他的突触能量是负电荷
but since his synaptic energy has a negative charge--
我可以用闪电的正电荷来吸引他的能量
I could use my lightning's positive charge
来吸引他的能量
to attract his energy.
-就像磁铁  -没错
- Like a magnet. - Exactly.
之后呢  你怎么在里面活下来
Then what? I mean, how are you gonna survive inside of there?
你的  你的神速力光环会保护你的是吗
Well, your-- your Speed Force aura should protect you, right?
如果它没有呢
What if it doesn't?
重力会在几秒钟把你压成
The gravimetric forces will crush you
亚原子那么小
to a subatomic size within seconds.
那不会发生的
That's not gonna happen.
神速力的强度远远超过
The Speed Force is a billion times stronger
任何重力
than any gravimetric force.
就算你活着进去了  我们也没有办法
Even if you do survive the entry, we don't have a way
在你出来时保证切斯特思想的完整性
of keeping Chester's mind intact on the way out.
我们需要量子计算机的
We'd need superconductive wiring
超导线路来实现这一点
from a quantum computer to do that,
据我所知  那些只存在于未来
and last time I checked, those only exist in the future.
诺拉
Nora.
我们的诺拉  她还能帮我们
Our Nora, she can still help us.
我的天  她的辅助护手
Oh, my God, her back-up gauntlet.
西斯科  它还在这
Cisco, it's still here.
那个护手有我们需要的导线
That gauntlet's gonna have the filament we need.
我会把它抽出来穿进你的西装里
I'll strip it out and thread it into your suit.
好的  拉尔夫  与此同时
Okay, in the meantime, Ralph,
你能和冰霜帮助中城警局疏散市区吗
can you and Frost help CCPD evacuate downtown?
冰霜准备好出来  并使用西斯科的礼物了
Frost is ready to come out and to use Cisco's present.
队长  你不该出来的
Captain, you shouldn't be out here!
这也是我的城市
It's my city too.
帮助这些人离开这里
Help these people get out of here.
是的  长官
Yes, sir!
不
No!
跑啊  老弟
Run, dude.
不用谢
You're welcome.
战衣已完成
Suit's finished.
很好
Okay, great,
等巴里把切斯特的意识带出来后
so when Barry gets Chester's consciousness out of there,
他该怎么利用那股能量
what is he supposed to do with that energy?
-你记得精神增强室吗  -记得  但是没用啊
- You remember the MAC? - Yeah, but it's not working.
是  但是结构的完整性足够强大来
No, but the structural integrity is strong enough
容纳突触能量
to contain synaptic energy.
而且我们已经把切斯特移进去了  所以...
Besides, we already moved Chester into it, so...
等等  什么  "我们"移动了切斯特
I'm sorry, what? "We" moved Chester?
没错
That's right.
虽然我很小  但我能臂力可不小
I may be small, but I can bench my body weight.
就这样
That's it.
此曲为Queen乐队的1980版《飞侠哥顿》(Flash Gordon)主题曲
从第一天起我就想在合适之时放这首歌了
I've been saving this for the right moment since day one.
有没有搞错  西斯科
Really, Cisco?
那家伙要去勇闯黑洞呢
The guy is running in and out of a black hole.
有道理
Good point.
时机到了  冲
That's your window, go!
-他多久能出来  -几秒钟
- How long before he comes out? - Seconds.
我猜的
I think.
-"你猜的"  -我猜的
- "You think"? - I think.
巴里
Barry?
巴里  听得见我说话吗
Barry, can you hear me?
巴里
Barry.
巴里  巴里  求你说话
Barry--Barry, please, say something.
宝贝  求你了
Babe, please.
巴里  我不能再失去你了
Please, Barry, I can't lose you too.
天啊
Oh, my God.
快来  我们走
Come on, let's go.
黑洞崩溃了
The black hole imploded.
切斯特
Chester?
听得见吗
Can you hear me?
回到这里  回到我们身边
Come back here, to us,
回到这具身体上  回归你自己
to this body, to yourself.
大家闹起来
What up, party people?
你是闪电侠
Hey--hey, you're the Flash.
有高速异能和闪电什么的
With the speeding around and the lightning and all that.
我是大粉丝  大粉丝
Hey, big fan, man, big fan.
还有  我在哪里
Also, where am I? -
本地新闻
闪电侠拯救城市  清理正在进行
切斯特好多了
Chester is doing so much better.
别误会  他还是  你懂的
I mean, don't get me wrong, he's still, you know,
眼睛里闪烁着橙色的暗能量
glowing in the eyes with orange dark energy,
但他精神很好
but he's in really good spirits.
他还要多久才能出来
How long until he gets out?
凯特琳说他的分子需要在亚原子水平上改变
Caitlin said his molecules need to destabilize at the subatomic level.
我觉得他还要在精神增强室里
My guess is he'll need to cook in the MAC
待上四到六周或者更久  直到他正常为止
for another four to six weeks, maybe more, until he's back to normal.
相信我  在此期间
Well, believe me, he is more than happy to chill here
他很乐意呆在尖端科研实验室
at S.T.A.R. Labs in the meantime.
等他出来了
And when he does get out,
他就知道自己想干什么了
that boy knows exactly what he wants to do.
绝对是约娜塔莉约会
Mm, definitely gonna ask Natalie out.
说到去约会
Speaking of going out,
卡米拉和我每周二都要去吃沙瓦玛
Kamilla and I are doing shawarma Tuesday,
所以我要闪人了
so I'm gonna mosey.
当然  在成为震波后  闪人就难多了
Of course, moseying is a lot harder these days post-Vibe.
开着尖端科研实验室专用车去约会
Showing up to a date in a S.T.A.R. Lab van,
不太雅观
not a good look.
不  我载你一程
Mm, no. I'll give you a ride.
然后冒着看上去像我妈送我的风险吗
And risk looking like my mom just dropped me off?
那更好  你可以自己走
Ooh, even better, you can walk.
好吧  我来了
Okay, I'm coming.
我从没想过
It never occurred to me
你想要过自己的生活
that you might want to live a life.
所以我才没让你掌舵
That's why I never offered to let you drive,
不是因为我觉得你只会打架
not because I think you're only good in a fight.
你确定吗
You sure?
我知道这很难
I know it's a really big ask,
我不想让你觉得有什么义务
and I don't want you feeling obligated or whatever.
冰霜  你总是陪着我
Frost, you have always been there for me,
保护着我
protecting me.
现在我可以为你做些事了
Now I get to do something for you.
而且  尽管我总感觉你是我的一部分
Besides, even though it's always felt like you were a part of me,
第一次  我感觉到我是你的一部分
for the first time, it feels like I'm a part of you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
随时效劳
Any time.
看来一切都很顺利如霜了
Guess everything's coming up frosty, huh?
我想是吧
Yeah, I guess.
我要从哪开始
Where do I start?
怎么才能  过自己的生活
How do you, you know, live a life?
当然要有一个生活导师
With a life coach, of course.
拉尔夫之书
首先要搞定的是  "杀手"这个名字
So, first thing's first: the name "Killer,"
对一些人来说有点过了
it's a little bit too much for some folks.
你有考虑过改一下吗
Have you thought about changing it?
我妈妈的中间名叫安妮
My mom's middle name is Anne.
阳性  99%细胞显示肿瘤标记
我绝不会接受死亡
I will never accept death,
不会像你一样
not like you did.
瑞秋·罗素
挚爱的母亲
1956-2019
噬血细胞综合征
标记检测量99%
是什么让你相信
So, what made you believe
你能带切斯特离开那个地方
that you could carry Chester out of that place?
是你让我相信我可以
You made me believe I could do it.
我意识到  我们可以做对方的互助小组
I realized we could be each other's support group,
尽管那需要花些时间
even though it's gonna take some time.
如果我们的内心能带着这样的记忆
If we can carry a memory like this together in our hearts,
那把一个人的意识从黑洞带出
carrying somebody's consciousness out of a black hole?
也是小菜一碟
It's a piece of cake.
况且  还有什么办法能让我把它还给你
Besides, how else could I get this back for you?
我知道没有诺拉的视频那么好
I know it's not as good as Nora's video...
比那个还要好
It's better.
现在我们有可以纪念诺拉的东西了
Now we have something that we can honor Nora with.
她真的很"酷炫"
She was pretty "Schway."
你想怎么样
What do you want?
让你们的宇宙存活
For your universe to survive.
那个基座
The plinth...
你毁了它
you destroyed it.
你毁了诺拉的信息
You destroyed Nora's message.
不幸的副作用
An unfortunate side effect.
但我需要阻止你们
But I needed to discourage you.
阻止我们什么
From doing what?
抱有希望
Hoping.
你的决心没有界限  闪电侠
Your determination is boundless, Flash--
这是你伟大的特质之一
it is one of your greatest qualities--
但你无法避免眼前的危机
but you cannot avoid the coming Crisis.
巴里在消失前还有五年时间
Barry has five years before he vanishes.
不再是了
No longer.
2019年12月10日
December 10, 2019.
在那一天  他会接受召唤
On that day, he will answer the call
并作出最后的牺牲
and make the ultimate sacrifice.
不久
Soon...
这个世界将为所有已知宇宙的命运抗争
this world will fight for the fate of all the known universes.
我不会离开我的家人
I'm not gonna leave my family.
一定有办法阻止即将到来的危险
There has to be a way to stop what's coming.
很抱歉
I am sorry,
但已经开启的事件
but events have been set into motion
是你不可能领悟的
that you cannot possibly comprehend.
我不需要理解它们
I don't need to understand them!
只管告诉我怎么做
Just tell me what I can do.
活下去
To survive?
你不能
You can't.
为了让几十亿人幸免于这次危机
In order for billions to survive this coming Crisis,
闪电侠必须死
the Flash must die.